{
    "id": "17f999c9572f41f8b8bb78d4d9eae7c7",
    "title": "Tenses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I ……………………… my grandparents about twice a month.",
            "description": "We use the simple present to talk about habits.",
            "answers": [
                "visit",
                "am visiting",
                "visits"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "04b809ead7f0496da169e21fb5064dc6"
        },
        {
            "question": "I ……………………… a lot of movies these days.",
            "description": "We use the present continuous to talk about actions and situations that are going on around now.",
            "answers": [
                "watch",
                "am watching",
                "will be watching"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "df7191652602488294cebd0791df1bd3"
        },
        {
            "question": "I asked her whether she …………………………. in God.",
            "description": "When the main verb is in the past tense, we usually use a past tense in the subordinate clause.",
            "answers": [
                "believes",
                "is believing",
                "believed"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "b5c28ef9a57a45d1bdd936e38761150d"
        },
        {
            "question": "I ………………………… him since our school days.",
            "description": "We use the present perfect to say how a long a present situation has been going on.",
            "answers": [
                "know",
                "have known",
                "am knowing"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "6bd41fe431d24ec783673c32df98ccd5"
        },
        {
            "question": "I …………………………… English since",
            "description": "We use the present perfect or the present perfect continuous tense to say how a long a present situation has been going on.",
            "answers": [
                "have taught",
                "have been teaching",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "713b1a5e245d4f31a7a16ac559b707b0"
        },
        {
            "question": "Where …………………. snakes live?",
            "description": "We use the simple present to talk about permanent situations.",
            "answers": [
                "do",
                "have",
                "did"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "5d3e0bb82ec041a9930d911e043db085"
        },
        {
            "question": "I ……………………… this fragrance very much.",
            "description": "The verb like is not normally used in the continuous form.",
            "answers": [
                "like",
                "am liking",
                "likes"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "a13b4b545cd94af79dcbcf1e427217d7"
        },
        {
            "question": "I promise I ………………………… this to anyone.",
            "description": "We do not normally use the simple present tense to talk about the future.",
            "answers": [
                "won't tell",
                "don't tell",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "b1c90a1a8ef6410f91fcc8465ac4e38b"
        },
        {
            "question": "We ………………………. to the movies tonight.",
            "description": "We use the present continuous to talk about a future event that has already been planned.",
            "answers": [
                "go",
                "have gone",
                "are going"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "cb09697a5ea14e8c9b59b987626583e1"
        },
        {
            "question": "I ………………………. my job tomorrow.",
            "description": "The simple present is used to talk about time tabled future events. The present continuous can also be used to talk about a pre-planned future event. ",
            "answers": [
                "am starting",
                "start",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "fa444c35b3a24fffaada7c43369d3851"
        },
        {
            "question": "Why ……………………… you take a holiday?",
            "description": "We mainly use the simple present tense in suggestions.",
            "answers": [
                "don't",
                "wouldn't",
                "haven't"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "2cfe915fd99f45e28613075a7ddcde5a"
        },
        {
            "question": "The climate …………………….. warmer.",
            "description": "The present continuous is used to talk about changing or developing situations.",
            "answers": [
                "gets",
                "will be getting",
                "is getting"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "a90bf40393324dc3abc4256a84f97e2c"
        }
    ]
}